[
    {
        "question": "On þissum geare ferde seo (<em>micel</em>) #### scipfierd eft on Englalande - In this year the great navy went again to England",
        "correctAnswer": "micele",
        "explanation":"Here 'micel' is modifying the singular nominative feminine 'scipfierd' so it takes the feminine 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "micela",
                "explanation": "An adjective takes the gender of its noun. As can be seen by 'seo', 'scipfierd' is feminine so 'micel' should take the feminine nominative 'e' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>yfel</em>) #### unrihtwisa cyning spræc mid his yflan tungan - The evil unrighteous king spoke with his evil mouth",
        "correctAnswer": "yfela",
        "explanation":"Here 'yfel' is modifying the singular nominative masculine 'cyning' so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "yfele",
                "explanation": "An adjective takes the gender of its noun. As can be seen by 'se', 'cyning' is masculine so 'yfel' should take the masculine nominative 'a' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<em>swet</em>) #### mete ðe hie heton monna se him cuom of hefonum - The sweet meats that they call mana which comes from heaven",
        "correctAnswer": "sweta",
        "explanation":"Here 'swet' is modifying the singular nominative masculine 'mete' so it takes the 'a' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "swete",
                "explanation": "An adjective takes the gender of its noun. As can be seen by 'se', 'mete' is masculine so 'swet' should take the masculine nominative 'a' ending"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Dol bið þæt (<em>lytel</em>) #### scip ðe gæð on deop wæter - Foolish is the little ship that goes in deep water",
        "correctAnswer": "lytle",
        "explanation":"Here 'lytel' is modifying the singular nominative neuter 'scip' so it takes the neuter 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "lytele",
                "explanation": "Adjectives with two syllables lose the vowel of the second syllable when they gain a suffix, so 'lytel' becomes 'lytle' when it gains the singular nominative neuter suffix 'e'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "On þissum geare sende he þone (<em>eald</em>) #### biscop Wulfstan to þæm stede þe wæs genemned Readingum - In this year he sent the old bishop to the place that was called Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "ealdan",
        "explanation":"Here 'eald' is modifying the singular accusative masculine 'biscop' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He sende þæt (<em>halig</em>) #### lic to þæm mynster - He sent the holy body to the minster",
        "correctAnswer": "halge",
        "explanation":"Here 'halig' is modifying the singular accusative neuter 'lic' so it takes the 'e' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "halgan",
                "explanation": "An adjective takes the gender of its noun. As can be seen by 'þæt', 'lic' is neuter so 'halig' should take the neuter accusative 'e' ending"
            },
            {
                "badAnswer": "halige",
                "explanation": "While the suffix is correct, adjectives with two syllables lose the vowel of the second syllable when they gain a suffix, so 'halig' becomes 'halge' when it gains the singular accusative neuter suffix 'e'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se ðe gebigde ðone (<em>heah</em>) #### heofonlican bigels - He who bowed the high vault of heaven",
        "correctAnswer": "heagan",
        "explanation":"Here 'heah' is modifying the singular accusative masculine 'bigels' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "heahan",
                "explanation": "Words ending in 'h' replace their 'h' with a 'g' before a suffix beginning with a vowel, so 'heah' becomes 'heagan' when it gains the ending 'an'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se deofol gesette hine uppan ðam scylfe ðæs (<em>heah</em>) #### temples - The devil set him upon the summit of the high temple",
        "correctAnswer": "heagan",
        "explanation":"Here 'heah' is modifying the singular genitive masculine 'temple' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "heahan",
                "explanation": "Words ending in 'h' replace their 'h' with a 'g' before a suffix beginning with a vowel, so 'heah' becomes 'heagan' when it gains the ending 'an'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He is in ðone deopan grund ðæs hatan leges and ðæs (<em>heard</em>) #### leges - He is in the deep abyss of the hot flame and the hard flame ",
        "correctAnswer": "heardan",
        "explanation":"Here 'heard' is modifying the singular genitive masculine 'leg' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt synt nu þæs foremeran ond þæs (<em>wis</em>) #### goldsmiðes ban Welondes? - What now are the bones of that renowned and wise goldsmith Weland?",
        "correctAnswer": "wisan",
        "explanation":"Here 'wis' is modifying the singular genitive masculine 'goldsmiðes' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða wicingas eodon þa to þære (<em>lytel</em>) #### iege þe is genemned Iona - The vikings then went to the little island that is named Iona",
        "correctAnswer": "lytlan",
        "explanation":"Here 'lytel' is modifying the singular dative feminine 'ieg' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "lytelan",
                "explanation": "While the suffix is correct, adjectives with two syllables lose the vowel of the second syllable when they gain a suffix, so 'lytel' becomes 'lytlan' when it gains the singular genitive feminine suffix 'an'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Woroldlicra weorca on ðam (<em>halig</em>) #### dæge geswice man georne - On that holy day, let men abstain from worldly works",
        "correctAnswer": "halgan",
        "explanation":"Here 'halig' is modifying the singular dative masculine 'dæg' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "haligan",
                "explanation": "While the suffix is correct, adjectives with two syllables lose the vowel of the second syllable when they gain a suffix, so 'halig' becomes 'halgan' when it gains the singular dative masculine suffix 'an'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic ðe hæbbe aþriet mid ðis (<em>lang</em>) #### spelle - I have bored you with this long speech",
        "correctAnswer": "langan",
        "explanation":"Here 'lang' is modifying the singular dative neuter 'spell' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ac uton don swa swa God tæhte þæt ure (<em>god</em) #### weorc beon on ða wisan mannum cuðe - But let us do as God has taught, that our good works may be so known to men",
        "correctAnswer": "godan",
        "explanation":"Here 'god' is modifying the plural nominative neuter 'weorc' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>heard</em>) #### þrowunga ðe he adreag - The hard sufferings than he endured",
        "correctAnswer": "heardan",
        "explanation":"Here 'heard' is modifying the plural nominative feminine 'þrowunga' so it takes the 'an' ending",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða (<em>eald</em>) #### wunde spræce þa ealdan race - The old wounds speak the old stories",
        "correctAnswer": "ealdan",
        "explanation":"",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "correctAnswer": "",
        "explanation":"",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "correctAnswer": "",
        "explanation":"",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "correctAnswer": "",
        "explanation":"",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "correctAnswer": "",
        "explanation":"",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "badAnswer": "",
                "explanation": ""
            }
        ]
    }
]